That's it, Max.
到此为止 麦克斯
Ifinidin Oplibion Nebila.
"伊菲尼丁‧欧普利比翁‧涅比拉"
Chaos theory observation cycle.
"混沌理论观测轮回"
The sphere will become a galactic whirlpool against the current.
球将化为逆流的银河漩涡
Its orbit will not be bound by physical laws,
将其轨道从物理的枷锁解放
it will turn into a comet and attack you.
变成彗星袭击你
Are you hitting to the right?
右边吗
Too bad, you guessed wrong.
真可惜 你猜反了
I have won. You were destined to treat me to coffee milk from the start.
赢定了 打从一开始你就注定 要请朕喝咖啡牛奶了
Wh-What? He hit it back!
什…什么 打回来了
He even used Nebila, which is the cycle's rotation.
还利用了"涅比拉"… 也就是"轮回"的回转
But…
不过…
it's all just child's play after all.
终究只是一场儿戏
Oh no, I broke the ball again.
糟糕 果然又打破了
No matter how many balls there are, they're never enough for you.
有几颗都不够用
(Level 1 Demon Lord and One Room Hero)
《Lv1魔王与独居废勇者》
(Episode 6: Battle at the Border)
(#6 国境线的攻防)
Sweating feels good.
流汗好舒服
Speaking of which, soaking in hot springs is extremely relaxing.
话说回来 泡温泉真不错
After all, we usually use a small bathroom.
毕竟我们平常是用系统式卫浴
And here we can stretch our legs.
还可以把脚伸直
We definitely made the right decision by coming here.
来这里是对的
Yeah.
是啊
Max, are you there?
麦克斯 你在那边吗
I'm here.
我在啊
Can you bring me a large towel?
可以帮朕拿大毛巾吗
I accidentally left it over there.
朕不小心忘在那边
I'll leave it here.
那我放在这里
Could you bring it in for me?
能不能帮我拿进来
I can't possibly walk into the room all wet, can I?
总不能全身湿答答走进房间吧
I really can't deal with you.
真拿你没办法
Then I'll open the door.
那我开门啰
I'm sorry, Max.
真抱歉 麦克斯
Here, open your mouth.
来 嘴巴张开
Stop messing around.
别蠢了
We don't need that.
不需要…
I had so much fun.
玩得好开心
What were we originally here for?
我们本来是来干嘛的
Attention all pedestrians,
请各位行人注意
we are the Republic's patrol team.
我们是共和国巡逻队
The border area between the Kingdom and the Republic is currently off-limits.
王国与共和国的国境一带 目前禁止靠近
That woman is from last time…
那女人是上次的…
I'm sorry for the inconvenience, please cooperate.
抱歉造成各位的困扰 还请配合
Furthermore, except for the direction towards the border,
另外 除了往国境方向的交通工具
all other transportation options are available as usual.
包含海陆与空路 皆可照常使用
We are the Republic's patrol team…
我们是共和国巡逻队…
She doesn't seem to have noticed us.
她好像没发现我们
Of course not.
那当然啊
Does her mention of the border imply a dispute with the Kingdom?
她说国境附近 这表示跟王国起了纷争吧
Is it okay? That's scary.
没问题吗 真可怕
Is a war imminent?
莫非要开战了吗
We should leave soon because things are not looking good.
可能不太妙 赶紧闪人吧
Old lady.
老太婆
You don't have to worry. This is all routine.
不用担心啦 这都是家常便饭
They occasionally fight near the border.
国境附近有事没事就会打起来
Eat it…
快吃吧…
Look,
你们看
the shops and the locals are all very calm, right?
像我们这种土产店和当地人 都很淡定吧
We've long been used to it.
早就习惯了啦
Indeed.
确实如此
This is what's called normalizing bias, right?
这就是所谓的正常化偏误吧
Eat up…
吃吧…
This might be a good opportunity.
或许是不可错失的良机
Alright, let's head to the border, Max.
好 前往国境吧 麦克斯
What kind of nonsense are you talking about?
你在讲什么蠢话
This is a good time to assess the Kingdom and Republic's strength.
岂不是个宝贵机会 确认王国与共和国双方的战力
And upon reflection,
而且仔细一想
we haven't done any reconnaissance since we arrived.
来了以后完全没做任何侦察活动
Nonsense. Go by yourself.
开什么玩笑 你自己去
I want to go home.
我要回家了
The return ticket is in my hands.
回程的票在朕手上
Even if you want to go home with a teleportation spell,
想靠传送咒语回家
only I can cast Teleportal, so you should give up.
也只有朕能使用朕的"转移路标" 死心吧
You bastard.
你这个混账
Speaking of which,
话说回来
how do you plan to get to the border?
你打算怎么去国境
You're not going to walk all the way, are you?
该不会要一路走过去吧
Leave it to me.
包在朕身上
-Yeah! -Come on, smile.
-耶 -来 笑一个
I'm in top form today.
朕今天状况绝佳
Is it because I soaked in the hot spring?
是不是因为泡了温泉
Let's fly to the border in one go.
一口气飞到国境吧
So heavy.
好重
I'm exhausted.
累死了
Geez. You're such an overweight luggage.
真是的 你这个超重的行李
Who told you to sleep after eating?
谁叫你吃饱就睡
You've put on weight.
变得这样肉肉的
Because the recent meals have been delicious…
还不是因为最近三餐吃得好
Just kidding.
开玩笑的
That simple stone wall is the border, right?
那个简陋的石墙就是国境吧
Let's stand by and watch, Max.
不妨来看热闹吧 麦克斯
Let me see.
我看看
Fire.
发射
Their way of fighting is always the same.
感觉跟平常一样
Yeah, so I asked the captain to go fishing.
对啊 所以我请团长去捕鱼了
It would be even more dangerous if we let the captain act rashly.
随便让团长出手 反而更危险嘛
In return.
回敬你们
Take this.
接招吧
Pull yourself together.
振作点
What is that toy?
那个玩具是什么
It's a weapon that can launch magic.
是可以发射魔法的兵器
Even humans who can't use magic
即便是不会魔法的人类
can use it for combat.
也能利用那个战斗
It's totally ineffective.
完全没效嘛
It's just like child's play.
根本是玩扮家家酒
If it were demon armies,
换作是我等魔之眷属的军队
we could simply tear through the stone wall like paper.
那道石墙就跟纸片没两样
Indeed.
就是说啊
Leaving the Republic aside, I don't think the magical weapons of
姑且不论共和国
the Kingdom wouldn't be able to break through such a wall.
我不认为王国的魔导兵器 攻不破那种城墙
The bombardment seems to be ineffective.
炮击似乎效果不佳
Of course, I know.
我当然知道
Damn it.
可恶
Perhaps the enemy has cast a high-level defense spell.
或许是因为使用了 高难度的防御咒语
Impossible.
不可能
They don't have such outstanding magic experts.
他们没有那么杰出的魔法高手
Or they have set up a powerful magic device.
或是设置了强力的魔导装置
A magical bombardment with a sleep or paralysis spell
再加上睡眠或麻痹咒语的魔导炮击
is also hard to deal with.
这东西同样难以对付
Although the enemy seems to have no intention of killing our troops…
虽然敌方似乎无意杀伤我军…
So what?
那又如何
No, never mind.
不 没什么
If we continue to fire magic cannons at each other, it will never end.
只是继续互射魔导炮 也解决不了任何事
I have an idea.
我有个想法
What?
什么
They've started to retreat.
他们开始撤退了
Deladora, good job.
德拉多拉 辛苦啦
They retreat so cleanly.
走得真干脆
Is anyone injured?
大家有没有受伤
No.
没有
Big sister, what should we do next?
大姐 等一下有什么计划
Anyway, we'll stay here and keep watch until tomorrow.
总之我们留下来 看守到明天
We also need to report to the captain…
也要先和团长报备…
Big sister.
大姐
Will, don't freeze.
威尔 不要傻住
Get down, prepare for battle.
快趴下 准备战斗
It's okay, I'll stop the bleeding right away…
没事的 我马上止血…
My hair is ruined.
我的秀发毁了
Shut up.
吵死人了
I can't believe it.
简直不敢相信
It actually penetrated this wall.
居然能够贯穿这道城墙
How is it, have you solved it?
如何 解决了没
I hit one of them in the arm.
击中了其中一人的手臂
Fire the next quickly,
快点发射下一发
or they'll escape.
不然要被他们逃了
Please let me concentrate.
请让我专心集中精神
I will need a lot of magical power to
想射穿那道城墙的防御咒语
break through that wall's defense spell.
需要凝聚大量的魔力
Let them flee if they want and leave the empty city.
逃了就逃了 反正会留下空城
We can slowly dismantle the empty city and fill the moat.
就能慢慢破坏 要填上壕沟也行
That magic just now was quite powerful.
刚才那招魔法挺厉害的
It seems they also have experts with great skills among them.
看来也有实力高超的好手
Finally, it's getting interesting.
终于比较有看头了
Here it comes.
来了
Yes, it's coming…
对啊 来了…
What are you looking at?
你在看什么
That is…
那是…
Captain.
团长
Leo.
雷奥
It's here…
来了…
Why is he always naked?
他怎么每次都光着身子
I felt the evil magic aura, so I rushed over.
我感觉到邪恶的"魔"之气息 便飞奔而来
Did I overthink it?
难道是我多虑了吗
General Leo.
雷奥将军
What are you still doing? Prepare for bombardment.
还在干什么 准备炮击
Only you…
唯有你这家伙…
I'll never forgive you.
我绝不原谅
How is this possible?
这怎么可能
Great, charge!
好耶 继续…
He really is childish.
他还真是幼稚
The captain is indeed amazing.
团长果然厉害
Super strong.
超强的
That wasn't magic, was it?
那招不是魔法吧
You monster.
你这个怪物
Captain Gelmof.
盖尔莫夫大尉
You took excellent care of me during my time in the kingdom's army.
在王国军时期 承蒙你诸多照顾
But if the kingdom's army continues its ways,
但假如王国军仍不改做法
we will not compromise either.
我们也绝不会妥协
Your resistance is meaningless.
都是无谓的抵抗
The Kingdom will attack again.
王国今后仍会向你们发动攻击
The Kingdom will never agree
你所期盼的和平谈判
to the peace talks you seek.
不可能获得同意
Captain, this is what you taught me.
大尉 这可是你教导我的
We must not give up,
不论眼前的难关多么漫长又艰苦
no matter how long and difficult the road ahead.
都不能轻言放弃
You know nothing at all.
你根本一无所知
The commander was so troubled because of you, you bastard.
长官为了你这混账 究竟有多么苦恼
You are the commander's nightmare.
你这家伙是长官的恶梦
As long as you're dead…
只要你死了…
That hit, didn't it?
那击命中了吧
A perfect hit.
完全正中
Go back and tell Fred,
回去告诉弗雷德
let's have a frank talk.
开诚布公 直接谈一场
So you don't have to worry about it.
这样就不必苦恼了吧
So, Captain,
那么 大尉
please go back today.
今天请先回去吧
Get out of my sight!
给我滚
Captain!
团长
What's wrong, big sister?
怎么了 大姐
Are you hurt? Are you okay?
妳受伤了吗 还好吗
I'm fine, it's just a minor scratch.
还好啦 只是小擦伤而已
Don't push yourself too hard.
不要太勉强自己
Are you sure you're okay?
真的没事吗
I'm fine…
没事…
Thanks, Captain.
谢谢团长
We couldn't contact you in time, but you arrived just in time.
还来不及联络 你就及时赶来了
I felt a peculiarly eerie aura of magic.
总觉得有一股特别诡异的魔之气息
Aura of magic?
魔之气息
Are you talking about that bald sorcerer?
你是说那位光头魔导士吗
No, I don't think it's him.
不 应该不是他
It appears that I was simply overthinking.
看来只是我多心了
It's fine, everything ended well anyway.
没关系 反正圆满落幕了
-What's with your head? -Enough, drop it.
-你的头怎么啦 -够了 别说了
You look more manly like this. Why not take off your sunglasses too?
这样更有男子气概 干脆拿掉墨镜吧
The sharp moves were admirable.
那利落的招数太令人佩服了
He's truly Leo.
不愧是雷奥
A country's ruler should be as strong as him.
一国之主都应该要像他一样强
Don't force your ideals onto others.
不要这样强人所难
We realized again why the Republic Gamma can compete with the Kingdom.
重新确认了 刚玛共和国为何能和王国抗衡
But on the other hand,
但是反过来说
this is equivalent to relying on Leo's combat power alone.
这等于是倚靠雷奥一人的战力
I wonder how long they can hold on.
不晓得还能撑多久
How about it, Max?
如何啊 麦克斯
Would you have a chance of beating Leo
看了雷奥战斗的模样
if you fought him right now?
假如现在跟他打一场 你有胜算吗
Are you kidding me?
别说笑了
I'm not even close to his level right now.
现在的我连他的脚趾头都比不上
That's not necessarily true.
那可不一定
Are you satisfied now, Your Majesty?
心满意足了吧 陛下
We can go back now.
可以准备回去了
You're right,
说得也是
I have witnessed Leo fight.
已经亲眼看到雷奥战斗
Let's go back today.
今天就先回去吧
You should thank me,
心怀感激吧
thanks to my teleportation spell,
多亏了朕的传送咒语
we can get home in a blink of an eye.
一转眼就能回家了
Did you bring everything?
东西都带了吧
No problem.
没问题啦
Move a little closer to me.
你再靠过来一点
Teleportal.
"传送"
Teleport quickly!
快点传送
He's catching up.
他追上来了
What happened?
出了什么事
Leo found us.
雷奥发现我们了
Teleport quickly!
快点传送
Wait, I can't concentrate on the spell.
等一下 朕无法专心念咒
Stop right there!
站住
He's here.
来了…
That spine-chilling magic aura.
那股毛骨悚然的"魔"之气息
You're not a human,
你这家伙绝非人类
you're the Demon Lord's subordinate, right?
莫非是魔王的手下
We can't escape.
逃不了
Your judgment is wise.
明智的判断
You're skilled, state your name.
你的身手不错 报上名来
Is it because of those glasses?
是因为那副鼻子眼镜
Thanks to those,
多亏了那个
Leo didn't recognize you as Max.
雷奥认不出你就是麦克斯
I-I see, I forgot about that.
原…原来如此 我都忘了
It's your voice.
原来是你的声音
Don't suddenly speak in my head.
不要突然在我的脑袋里讲话
I had no choice.
朕也是逼不得已
It would be terrible if Leo heard us.
被雷奥听到的话就惨了
Why aren't you speaking?
怎么不说话
I asked you to state your name.
我叫你报上名来
Although I think you're probably a spy sent by the Kingdom.
虽然八成是王国派来的间谍
Quickly think of a way to bluff your way out.
快点想办法蒙混过去
T-That's not true.
才…才不是呢
We were just passing by.
我们只是刚好路过而已
Your explanation is inadequate.
哪有人转移话题的借口这么烂
Damn, what do you want me to do then?
吵死了 不然你说要怎么办
You said you were just passing by?
刚好路过
The roads to the border should have been closed.
照理说通往国境的路都禁止通行了
He actually believed it.
居然接受了
Honestly, I don't want to deal with you.
老实说我才懒得管你这家伙
The problem is that guy,
问题是那家伙
he looks like a child, but I did feel
外表看似小孩 但我确实感受到了
an inscrutable evil magic power.
深不可测的邪恶"魔"之力
Wh-What are you talking about?
你…你在说什么
This child is my child.
这孩子是我生的
-M-Mom. -What is it?
-妈…妈妈 -怎么啦
You actually brought a demon clan here.
居然带魔族闯进来
What are your intentions?
到底有何居心
If you continue to play dumb,
假如你想继续装傻
I won't show any mercy.
我也不会手下留情
How about this?
不如这样好了
Hand over that demon clan to me.
把那个魔族交给我
As long as you do as I say, I will let you go.
只要你照办 我就放你一马
Max, you should do as he says for now.
麦克斯 还是先照他说的做
Don't worry, I can use the teleportation spell.
别担心 朕还能用传送咒语
As long as there's a chance, I can escape at any time.
只要有机可乘 朕随时都能逃
A chance? Do you think he will show a vulnerability?
有机可乘 你觉得他会露出破绽吗
Don't worry.
放心吧
Even if something unexpected happens,
即使有什么万一
as the demons, we can resurrect.
我等魔之眷属也能复活
It's no big deal.
没什么大不了
That's true.
这么说也是
Alright, hand me over to him.
好了 把朕交给他吧
At the very least, I have to let you escape.
至少要让你逃走才行
I don't want to.
我不要
Why should I listen to you, long-haired man?
谁要乖乖听你的 长发男
I like you.
令我中意
I'll go distract him for about ten seconds.
我去争取十秒左右的时间
You take the chance to focus and finish the teleportation spell.
你趁机集中精神 念完传送咒语
You're indeed not ordinary.
你果然不是等闲之辈
You must never stop chanting under any circumstances.
无论如何都不要停止咏唱
Hurry.
动作快
No matter what…
无论如何…
I won't stop.
都不会停下
Playing trick?
耍什么小聪明
I won.
赢定了
You are…
你是…
You actually dodged that kick. Who are you?
居然能闪过那记踢击 你到底是谁
You still can't tell? You must be kidding.
这样还看不出来 骗人的吧
We did it, Max.
成功了 麦克斯
Fantastic.
好极了
What? Max?
什么 麦克斯
You idiot, don't shout out my name.
你这个蠢蛋 不要叫出名字
I-I'm sorry.
对…对不起
Max? I see, no wonder.
麦克斯 原来如此 怪不得
Let's escape first.
先逃再说
Hold on, Max.
等等 麦克斯
What are you up to?
你到底在打什么主意
Why did you come here? No,
为什么会来这里 不对
why are you with the demon clan? You…
你为什么会跟魔族在一起 你…
It's my privacy. I refuse to answer any of it.
这是我的私事 一概拒绝回答
Long time no see.
好久不见
I'm glad you seem to be doing well.
幸好你看起来过得不错
I see, so that's why…
是吗 这也是当然的
So he is Max.
原来是麦克斯
No wonder…
怪不得…
Exhausted.
好累
We're home.
回家了
It hurts so much.
痛死我了
We finally made it back safely.
总算平安回来了
This room makes me feel inexplicably nostalgic.
莫名觉得怀念
Leo is incredibly strong.
雷奥那家伙真是强得惊人
Yeah.
是啊
But you're not any less impressive.
不过你也毫不逊色喔
You fought brilliantly.
打得非常精彩
Did I?
是吗
A hot spring bath is really nice.
泡温泉真不错
Is there something wrong, Your Majesty?
有事吗 陛下
What's the matter?
您怎么了吗
-Max, -Don't stare at me with the Third Eye.
-麦克斯 -不要用第三只眼紧盯着我
What's going on with you?
到底是怎么了
You protected me.
你保护了朕
I wanted to…
朕想…
Thank you.
谢谢你
You're welcome.
别客气
Don't get me wrong.
你可别会错意
If it were just me, I could have escaped instantly.
如果只有朕一人 立刻就能逃走
Alright, alright.
好啦好啦
I'm going to kill you guys.
我要杀了你们
Hurry up and fix the paper door.
还不快点把拉门修好
Only now have I realized this trip was quite enjoyable.
结束后才发现 这趟旅行挺开心的
Right?
对吧
What nonsense are you talking about? I'm not doing this anymore.
说什么蠢话 我再也不奉陪了